<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://gregorysech.github.io/personal_blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://gregorysech.github.io/personal_blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-10T02:32:36-05:00</updated><id>https://gregorysech.github.io/personal_blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Gregory Sech</title><subtitle>Gregory Sech's blog with Jupyter Notebooks thanks to Fastpages.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">First post up, Nice.</title><link href="https://gregorysech.github.io/personal_blog/github-pages/2020/04/19/First-post-up-Nice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First post up, Nice." /><published>2020-04-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://gregorysech.github.io/personal_blog/github-pages/2020/04/19/First-post-up-Nice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gregorysech.github.io/personal_blog/github-pages/2020/04/19/First-post-up-Nice.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;post-publishing-and-moments-of-panic&quot;&gt;Post publishing and moments of panic.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after doing some little personalization (basically some pruning and setting 
up the About me section) it’s time to make history.&lt;br /&gt;
Git add, commit, push and now we wait for the deploy actions to do their job.&lt;br /&gt;
After letting out my cat I notice that the Actions are all green!&lt;br /&gt;
YES, success!&lt;br /&gt;
I rush to click on the link in the README and 404, page not found :(&lt;br /&gt;
Panic ensures. What did I do wrong? &lt;br /&gt;
Is it a browser caching problem? CTRL+shift+R, nope :/&lt;br /&gt;
Is it because the repository was originally 
private?&lt;br /&gt;
Searching mechanism settles in and I stumple upon a Github Community post with 
a similar problem, hopefully someone else had found a simple solution.&lt;br /&gt;
Someone advices to choose a Jekyll theme however I do not have a selector like 
in their screenshot I only have the Source brench dropdown available and with 
the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; branch selected.&lt;br /&gt;
Let’s check what that branch contains, looks like a processed static website, 
at least the website build Action is working.&lt;br /&gt;
I’mma try changing the branch and then changing it back: the good, old, shut 
down and restart.&lt;br /&gt;
Kinda happy that this worked however the prespective of doing this everytime is 
daunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;so-what-now&quot;&gt;So, what now?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is kind of the first time blogging so, to tranquilize myself, I’ll expose a
kind of roadmap of topics that will be written about.&lt;br /&gt;
I really enjoy studying data analysis, both the theoretical part and the 
practical component.&lt;br /&gt;
So my “serious” posts will start with an introduction of the concepts of data 
analysis. I cannot assure how many personal posts I will publish before the 
first technical one but I hope not many.&lt;br /&gt;
I have no expectencies about who will read this blog so I will try to start from
some pretty basic concepts of statistics and machine learning.&lt;br /&gt;
This will be a pretty useful experience also to review my knowledge before the 
start of the next academic year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Post publishing and moments of panic.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting my adventure with fastpages.</title><link href="https://gregorysech.github.io/personal_blog/introduction/fastpages/jupyter/2020/04/19/Starting-my-adventure-with-fastpages.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting my adventure with fastpages." /><published>2020-04-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://gregorysech.github.io/personal_blog/introduction/fastpages/jupyter/2020/04/19/Starting-my-adventure-with-fastpages</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gregorysech.github.io/personal_blog/introduction/fastpages/jupyter/2020/04/19/Starting-my-adventure-with-fastpages.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;about-me-this-blog-and-i&quot;&gt;About me, this blog and I&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Gregory Sech, currently I’m a Computer Science student at Ca’Foscari 
University of Venice pursuing a Data Science curriculum.&lt;br /&gt;
During the COVID-19 pandemic I’ve had time to ponder quite a lot about what my 
life was leading to and what mistakes I did and what I needed to change about 
my mindset to have a positive impact on this world.&lt;br /&gt;
I do not have the presumption to being able to change the world however I do 
belive that I am not doing enough, especially I never really wanted to share 
my thoughts and my experiences to others. &lt;br /&gt;
I decided to start this blog to share some experiences, it will not always be 
about Data Science, heck, it might take a while before the first “real” Data
Science post to be published. I’d like this blog to be a kind of a journal where
I will share with whoever finds this fragments of my experiences and thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;fastpages-a-choice-of-laziness-procrastination-and-actions&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fastpages&lt;/code&gt;: a choice of laziness, procrastination and Actions.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m lazy and I will probably always be.&lt;br /&gt;
My laziness is at the core of my passion for Computer Science.&lt;br /&gt;
I really didn’t want to write code or become an expert in CI/CD to integrate 
Jupyter Notebooks in my blog, also I didn’t want to create a conversion and 
embedding process from scratch.&lt;br /&gt;
While I was researching how to use GitHub Actions to automatically export them 
and commit the result in a different repository I came across &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fastpages&lt;/code&gt; and 
looked like a perfect fit.&lt;br /&gt;
Obviously I had to procrastinate a little before getting on board with the idea 
so I watched the third movie of the Millenium saga while chatting with friends 
over Discord, played some videogames and then went to sleep. All of this 
yesterday.&lt;br /&gt;
Today I woke up quite early and unable to sleep I decided of rolling up my 
sleeves and starting to integrate this bad boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-first-hour-or-so-with-fastpages&quot;&gt;My first hour or so with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fastpages&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first half an hour were pretty simple, I’ve ended reading most of the 
readme about &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fastpages&lt;/code&gt; and discovered that to use it locally I had to install
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docker-compose&lt;/code&gt;, instruments I’m familiar with thankfully.&lt;br /&gt;
So on my terminal I installed and added myself to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; group to use 
that without &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; privileges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;apt &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;docker.io
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;gpasswd &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$USER&lt;/span&gt; docker
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;apt &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;docker-compose
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This and rebooting the machine did the trick.&lt;br /&gt;
As described by the documentation I created a new GitHub repository using the 
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fastpages&lt;/code&gt; template followed the initialization PR instructions to setup the 
deployment keys and discovered that I had to make the repository public to have 
free access to GitHub Pages, fair enough.&lt;br /&gt;
Now I’ve cloned the repository locally and started the website with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;make server&lt;/code&gt;
to start editing the website.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve got some problem with my first markdown post but I discovered that I 
forgot to add the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;layout: post&lt;/code&gt; directive to the post &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Front matter&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
I’m quite happy with the start of this process, it was mostly painless, I’ll 
just customize a little more the blog and then publish everything.&lt;br /&gt;
If I do not procrastinate too much I hope to write about the publishing process
in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">About me, this blog and I</summary></entry></feed>